DAYS!
In the State of Qin and the State of Wei's fierce battle, Xin and Lun Hu have faced off once again.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秦国(しんこく)と魏国(ぎこく)との
激戦の中で 再び対峙(たいじ)した信(しん)と輪虎(りんこ)
Which one will surpass their limits
and continue on their path?
限界を超え 己の道を貫き通すのは
果たして どちらか
２人の熱き思いが今 火花を散らす
These two's heated emotions are now making sparks fly.
（廉頗(れんぱ)）さっさと下りてこい！
一騎打ちでカタをつけるぞ
Hurry and get down here!
We'll settle this one-on-one!
I don't mind fighting empty handed!
こっちは素手でも かまわんぞ
（馬令）殿…
My lord...
（蒙驁(もうごう)）人の おちょくり方も
変わっておらぬわ
The way he teases people hasn't changed a bit.
だが それは それで うれしいわい
But I'm actually quite happy with this.
Okay, let's get started!
（蒙驁）よし 始めるぞ！
（馬令）ははっ！
Yes, sir!
Take your positions!
配置に就け！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（兵士）全兵を呼べ！ 急げ！
Call all soldiers!
Hurry!
ノリ悪し ハハハハッ…
Looks like he's not game for it.
The Final Plan
（兵士）ンンッ…
やはり廉頗１人ではなかった
I knew Lian Po wasn't alone.
そりゃそうだろう…
（兵士）どうなってんだ？ これは
Well, of course.
What's going to happen here?!
The primary purpose of the headquarters made up of the Great General and his staff officers
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）大将と その幕僚からなる
本営の最大の目的にして 責務とは
is to establish a map of the entire war and lead their army to victory.
その戦いの全体図を描ききり
自軍を勝利に導くことである
そして 双方の描いた その設計図の
作りは 共通する部分もあった
And that blueprint the two sides created have certain parts in common.
While Meng Ao and Lian Po were enemies,
蒙驁と廉頗
敵同士でありながらも ２人の心は
極めて近く寄り添っていたのである
each ones's thoughts were exceedingly close to the other's.
The map of this war I drew...
（蒙驁）
わしが描いた今回の戦の全体図
had the main army, the central army, as a shield...
本軍である中央軍をあえて盾とし
廉頗の中央軍の攻撃を
まずは 徹底的に受け止める
and would first thoroughly stop Lian Po's central army's attack.
And in that interim, the two mighty generals Huan Ji and Wang Jian would form our main attack
そして その間に 強力な攻撃力を
持つ桓騎(かんき) 王翦(おうせん)の両副将を―
Qin
Wei
攻撃の主軸とし 左右から進撃
and charge from the left and the right.
They would then crush their oppositions and push onward to the enemy headquarters.
相対する魏国軍を撃破し
そのまま本陣を狙う
我が魏国軍の攻撃の主力は
あくまでも中央の輪虎軍
The main force of my State of Wei Army's attack
is undoubtedly the Lun Hu Army in the center.
だが 左右の軍を
敵副将たちに当たらせ
However
if I have my armies on the left and right attack their respective Vice Generals,
撃破 もしくは押し込みを図る
they will crush or push though their opponents.
They will then turn inwards to Meng Ao's headquarters.
そして
そのまま 蒙驁本陣に回り込む
In other words...
（蒙驁）つまり…
（廉頗）中央 左右と
３つの戦場から組み立てる
I have constructed the three battlefields of the center, the left, and the right.
（蒙驁）同じ戦略
The same strategy.
（廉頗）
まあ これは誰でも思い至ること
Of course, this something anybody could think up.
だが 問題は ここからだ
（蒙驁）その対応は分かれた
The real issue is what comes next.
The way those battlefields are being handled differ.
わしは 守りに徹するように命じた
I've ordered my army to defend with all their strength.
（廉頗）わしは攻めに出た
I've issued commands to attack.
そして 勝った
And we've won, of course.
当然じゃ
玄峰(げんぽう)は 早々に散ったものの―
While Xuan Feng was taken out fairly early,
Jie Zifang later advanced.
そのあとに介子坊(かいしぼう)の軍が押し寄せた
When they enter battle, the State of Qin Army's main force, the Huan Ji Army, has been silent.
つぶし合いに入って
秦国軍の主力の一方 桓騎軍は―
沈黙した
それだけでも こちらは優勢
That alone is enough to give us predominance.
And what's tilted the state of war above all is...
そして何よりも 戦局を大きく
傾かせたのは 右の戦場だったな
the right battlefield.
When I dispatched the army directly under me, the Wang Jian Army retreated far back.
わし直属の軍が出たことで
王翦軍は 後方深くに後退
No... they ran.
否… 逃げていきおった
Meng Ao, wouldn't you say that's a pretty big miscalculation on your part?
蒙驁よ さすがに
これは大誤算ではなかったのか？
頼りの もう片方の主軸が
機能を失ったうえに―
Not only has the other side of your main force which you're relying on lost its ability to function,
わしに 本陣背後を
突かせてしまったのだからな
I've pierced the back of your headquarters.
The reason I gave Bai Guixi the title of Great General
わしが 白亀西(はくきさい)に大将を譲ったのも
この図を
初めから思い描いていたからだ
is because I expected this map to play out from the beginning.
After that, all I needed was for Lun Hu to break through the center.
あとは輪虎が中央を突破すればいい
わしは背後を突く
Then I would attack the rear.
前後から
挟み撃ちで 本陣を落とすだけだ
With a pincer attack from the front and the rear, we would take down the headquarters.
（蒙驁）フォフォフォ…
うろたえることはない
There's no need to panic.
Against him, I am always a "loser".
ヤツの前では
いつでも わしは敗者だ
（馬公）殿…
My lord?
（蒙驁）本陣の全軍を後ろに回せ
（馬令）ぜ… 全軍を？
Send all of the headquarter's armies to the rear.
A-All armies?!
（馬令）しかし それでは 正面の
中央軍が抜かれたときの手だてが…
But then what means of defense will we have when the central army is penetrated?
かまわぬ
I'm not concerned.
廉頗よ
Lian Po, I've lost to you every time in the past.
おぬしに負け続けた わしじゃ
こうなることも予想はしていた
So I've predicted that something like this would happen.
予想ができたということは―
And having predicted it means...
対処ができるということじゃ
そして…
I've prepared for it.
And so...
この砦(とりで)こそ おぬしを
討つためだけに築いた いわば―
I constructed this stronghold for the purpose of you attacking it.
One might call it...
蒙驁流 対廉頗迎撃布陣
a Meng Ao-style Lian Po intercepting formation!
フン…
（従者Ａ）
裏側に これほどの準備を…
He had this much prepared in the back of his headquarters?
（従者Ｂ）守備偏重で
隙が少ないとは聞いていたがな
I'd head he overemphasizes defense and leaves very few gaps, but...
（従者Ｃ）
うん？ いや ちょっと待て
No, wait.
ハハハハッ… よく見ろ あの砦
Take a good look at that stronghold!
Yeah. It's really ill-formed looking and full of unnecessary parts.
（従者Ｂ）
ああ なんとも不格好でムダが多い
（廉頗）いや…
No... this isn't bad.
これは悪くない
With that average style of yours, you've polished up a few things, haven't you, Meng Ao?!
凡人なりに
多少は練ってあるではないか 蒙驁
Of course.
（蒙驁）当たり前じゃ
長年 考えに考えを重ねた布陣じゃ
This is a formation I spent many years developing.
All in order to defeat you if I someday ended up in a battle against you.
いつの日か
おぬしと戦うハメになったとき
おぬしを討ち取るためにな
う～む…
これは ひと筋縄では いかんのぅ
This is no ordinary tactic.
騎馬が多すぎる
半数を馬から下ろせ
We have too many mounted units. Have half of them get off their horses.
Yes, sir!
The bow unit will act as usual.
弓隊を いつものように！
盾兵を前に出して矢を受けさせろ
Shield soldiers should move forward to block arrows.
Yes, sir!
Okay, here we go, Meng Ao.
さ～て いくぞ 蒙驁　その首…
I'm going to lop off that head of yours with my own hands.
この手で たたき落としてくれる
（李充(りじゅう)）あっ！ 敵が動きだしたぞ
The enemy is moving!
（馬令）
廉頗は どこから攻めてくる？
Where is Lian Po attacking from?!
My lord!
（郭叫(かくきょう)）殿…
Come get me, Lian Po!
来てみよ 廉頗
この砦に入らば 死ぬのは おぬしだ
If you enter this stronghold, the one to die will be you!
（壁(へき)）周囲の警戒を怠るな
Maintain vigilance!
我々同様 この辺りを
さまよっている敵兵がいるぞ
There are enemy soldiers wandering around this area just like us!
Yes, sir!
（壁）しんがりの役は果たしたが
We've fulfilled our duty as the rear guard,
王翦本隊と はぐれたうえに
道にも迷った
but not only have we separated from the Wang Jian main unit, we're also lost.
ほかの隊も吸収し
それなりの戦力は残っている
Though we've absorbed other units so we have some considerable fighting power now.
We need to get back to the front line quickly...
早く前線に復帰せねば…
壁さま あれは…
（壁）うん？
Lord Bi! Look!
蒙驁将軍の本陣… こんな所まで
迷って来てしまったのか
General Meng Ao's headquarters?
We drifted all the way here?
ま… まさか
敵に迫られているのか？
I... It can't be! It's being approached by enemies?!
Lian Po is moving!
廉頗が動いたぞ！
（兵士）た… 隊長！
C-Captain! Lian Po is heading this way!
廉頗が こちらに！
（隊長）あ… 慌てるな
D-Don't lose your head!
（隊長）フン… バカめ
かかりおったな 廉頗
That fool! We've got you now, Lian Po!
One of the oldest tricks in the book is to attack from the side to avoid an arrow onslaught.
（隊長）矢の雨を避けるため
端から攻めるは定石
だから あらかじめ
側面の林に弓隊を隠している
And in anticipation of that, we hid a bow unit in the forest on the side.
正面と側面から矢を受ければ
いかに廉頗とて ひとたまりもない
If he's pelted with arrows both from the front ant the sides,
even Lian Po won't stand a chance!
ハハハッ！
さすが“伝説の武将”廉頗
Just what I'd expect from the legendary military commander, Lian Po!
既に 戦が古いわ！
His fighting style is outdated!
射(う)て！
Fire!
（兵士たち）ウワーッ！
A-Are they insane?!
（隊長）き… 気は確かか？
なぜ 味方に矢を打ち込む！
Why are they firing arrows at their allies?!
My lord, what in the world is this?!
（李充）殿 これは 一体…
（蒙驁）側面の林は―
The forest on the side has already fallen into the enemy's hands.
既に 敵の手に落ちたのじゃ
ヒッ… ヒイッ…
（隊長たち）ウワーッ！
L-Lian Po just...
（李充）れ… 廉頗が あっさりと
（馬令）１段目が抜かれるぞ！
got up the first step that easily?!
The right edge was defeated as well!
（郭叫）右の端も やられた！
（馬令）殿…
Lord!
Do not panic.
案ずるな　この砦の恐ろしいのは…
The true ferocity of this stronghold is only just about to become apparent.
ここからじゃ
That's it!
（魏兵）
いいぞ！ こっちは敵が手薄だ！
The enemy is short-handed over here!
（魏兵）いける！
（魏兵）蒙驁を八つ裂きにするぞ！
We can make it!
Let's rip Meng Ao limb from limb!
な… なに！
（魏兵）これは…
Wh-What?
What is this?
A dead end?!
行き止まり！
What's wrong, move forward!
どうした？ 前
（兵士）何だ？
What?!
い… いかん！ 下がれ！
N-No, go back!
Now, fire!
（弓隊）今だ！ 射て！
（飛来音）
（魏兵たち）ウワーッ！
General... Ally units are being beaten all over.
（側近Ａ）将軍… あちこちで
味方の隊がやられているようです
フン…“断道の計”
A cut-road plan.
道を断ち
敵を追い詰めるための策略だ
It's a strategy where you cut off the roads in order to corner the enemy.
Unlike Wang Jian's fortress that didn't have a vulnerability to it,
一分の隙もなかった王翦の砦と違い
蒙驁の これは
一見 不格好で隙だらけだ
at first glance, Meng Ao's is clumsily put together and covered with openings.
しかし いざ上ってみると―
But it's actually crowded with dead-end roads that you can't see from below.
下からは見えなかった
行き詰まる道が ひしめいている
That is all a part of Meng Ao's plan. If someone is led to one of those areas, it turns into a hunting ground.
それは 蒙驁が仕組んだもので
ハマれば 格好の狩り場と化す
蒙驁は このワナを砦全体に
迷路のごとく張り巡らせておるのだ
He set these up all around his stronghold like a maze.
ここは 守備の砦にあらず
This is no defensive stronghold.
It is clearly a stronghold for attacking an invading enemy.
明らかに
入ってきた敵を迎え撃つ砦だ
蒙驁め　本気で このわしを
討ち取るつもりのようじゃ
Meng Ao, you old fox, you really intend to take me down, don't you?
（李充）すごい！
Incredible!
（郭叫）敵の足を止めるどころか
殲滅(せんめつ)している！
Not only is the enemy being halted, they're being annihilated!
（馬令）
さすが 殿自ら考案された布陣だ
You've truly outdone yourself with this formation, my lord!
（郭叫）
言われるがままに作り込んだが
こんな仕掛けになっておるとは…
We'd made it just as you instructed, but...
I never expected the traps to be anything like this...
いやはや 驚きました
I'm astonished!
What's truly astonishing is how Lian Po was even prepared for a surprise attack.
（馬令）いや 驚くべきは 廉頗の
奇襲にまで備えられていたことだ
Did you know, my lord?
分かっておられたのですか？ 殿
ヤツが来ることが
That he was coming?
As a military commander, Lian Po has many faces.
（蒙驁）廉頗は 武将として
いくつもの顔を持っておる
Sometimes he's the "wise general" who makes a detailed plan before the battle starts,
（蒙驁）開戦前は
緻密な計画を立てる知将となり
戦が始まれば 戦局の推移を
直感的に見抜く本能型にもなる
and sometimes he's the "instinctual type" that detects the changes of the state of battle intuitively after it starts.
いったん 守備と決め込めば―
So say he's fighting defensively,
he becomes a general with an iron-wall defense like he was defending Changping from sieges for two years.
長平(ちょうへい)で２年 籠城したような
鉄壁の守りの将と化す
攻め時と見れば
正攻法 奇策を問わず―
And when he's attacking, he forgets about proper methods and clever schemes
必殺の勢いで攻めてくる剛将となる
and becomes a "strong general", one that attacks with lethal force.
そして そのときは
自ら 先陣を切ることも珍しくない
In those situations, it's not uncommon for him to lead a formation himself.
Those times are due to him being a bit too brave for his own good.
それは ヤツが あまりにも
勇猛であること　そして―
And... those are the rare occasions where he's a showoff.
希代の目立ちたがり屋ゆえじゃ
フォフォフォ…
じゃから読めた
So I foresaw that.
W-Well done, my lord. Truly admirable.
（馬令）さ… さすが殿です
敬服いたしました
しかし よくぞ
そこまで廉頗のことをご存じで
But... I'm amazed you know so much about Lian Po...
うむ…
I know so much about him from my memory of losing to him again and again when I was young.
若きころ あやつに
負け続けた記憶からだけでも―
廉頗のことは よく分かっている
だが それだけではない
But that is not all.
It has been about 40 years since I moved to the State of Qin.
秦国へ移ってから およそ40年
廉頗と戦うことは一度もなかったが
Since then, I never once fought Lian Po...
廉頗の戦いは 全て
その内容の隅々まで把握している
but I learned every last detail about Lian Po's battles.
その情報収集のために 大金を使い
I used quite a lot of money to collect that information
and I even personally went to observe wars at times.
時には
自ら ひそかに観戦に向かった
そうじゃ
Yes... I've always been watching that Lian Po.
わしは ずっと―
廉頗を見てきたのじゃ
Lian Po
（信）こっから先は通さねえぞ！
（輪虎）フッ…
I'm not letting you past here!
（尾平(びへい)）信！
Xin!
Xin's giving it all he's got over there,
信が あんだけやってんだ
俺たちも負けてらんねえぞ！
so we can't let ourselves get beaten, either!
（兵士）飛信隊に負けるな！
（兵士）我らの力を示せ！
Don't let the Fexin Unit win!
Show them just how powerful we are!
Where the hell are you looking?!
どこ見てやがる この野郎！
Now...
今だ！
The other units are joining with us.
ほかの隊が我らに合流してきている
（側近Ｂ）あまり増えると
行き詰まったとき 戻れぬぞ
If we get too big, we won't be able to turn back if we hit a dead end!
ハハハハッ！
案ずるな　わしに任せよ
Don't panic. Leave that to me!
（伝者）新しい報告が！
A new report!
昨日 右軍に廉頗将軍が現れ
Yesterday, General Lian Po appeared in the right army.
And it seems they pushed the Wang Jian Army quite a ways back!
そのまま 王翦軍を
後方深くまで押し込んだもようです
（李牧(りぼく)）うむ…
The general went off to the right himself?
（カイネ）将軍自ら 右に？
（李牧）蒙驁はマズイですね
Meng Ao looks like he's in trouble.
今ごろ 廉頗将軍に
背後を突かれていることでしょう
He's probably being attacked by General Lian Po from the rear right now.
（軍師）やはり
蒙驁の雪辱は ならぬようですな
I suppose Meng Ao won't be vindicating his honor, then.
（李牧）
うん？ どういうことですか？
What do you mean?
はぁ？ あっ いや…
Oh, nothing.
When Meng Ao lived in the State of Qi,
蒙驁は 斉(さい)の国にいたころ
廉頗将軍に負け続けていましたから
he had continuous losses against General Lian Po.
Of course, I have no way of knowing if Lian Po remembers that.
廉頗本人が
それを覚えているかは不明ですが
蒙驁にとっては
数十年ぶりの雪辱戦であると
but for Meng Ao, this is his first chance at vindication in several decades.
いえ
私も もともと斉国の人間でしてね
You see, I am originally from the State of Qi.
So I'm actually quite interested in the outcome of this...
ちょっと感慨深いものも…
言っておりませんでしたか？
Didn't I tell you?
り… 李牧さま？
L-Lord Li Mu?
I really wish you'd told me that sooner.
もっと早く言ってほしかった
（軍師）えっ？
（カイネ）李牧さま？
Lord Li Mu?
I think General Lian Po may be an exception,
（李牧）廉頗将軍に限って まず
そんなことはないと思いますが
強き武将が足をすくわれるとき
そこには 必ず油断があります
but when strong generals have the rug pulled out from under them, they always let their guard down.
When I fight, I always do everything I can to make my opponent neglect something.
私などは 戦うとき 相手を
油断させることに力を尽くします
もし 将軍が
蒙驁のことを覚えてるとしたら―
If the general remembers Lian Po,
that is enough to give Meng Ao an advantage.
それだけで 蒙驁は有利です
Because whichever side wins
勝っていた側は―
勝手に 相手の器のほどを
決めつけてしまいますからね
decides just to what extent the caliber of the opponent he faced was.
（カイネ）どうされました？
What's wrong?
（李牧）
いや そうです　それだけではない
Oh, that's right.
That isn't all.
もし 蒙驁が廉頗に対して 胸の奥に
秘めるものを持っているとしたら…
If Meng Ao holds Lian Po as a
special sort of objective...
だとしたら蒙驁は対廉頗のため―
then it's possible that he used those 40 years to develop a strategy against Lian Po.
40年は 作戦を練る時間が
あったということになります
I don't know what to think now.
これは分からなくなってきましたよ
もし 蒙驁が廉頗の持つ蒙驁像を
少しでも上回れば…
If Meng Ao exceeds the image of the Meng Ao that Lian Po holds by even a little, then...
（柵を壊す音）
こっちじゃ！
This way!
Dammit! We just can't catch the Lian Po unit in a trap!
（馬令）
くそ！ 廉頗隊だけワナにかからぬ
（朱可）ンンッ… 運のいいヤツめ
Lucky bastards!
ふむ…
（廉頗）こっちじゃ！
（側近Ａ）今度は下へ？
This way!
Now we're moving down?!
（馬令）あっ またワナをかわした
（朱可）ま… まさか―
They dodged another trap!
C-Could it be...
Lian Po knows where the traps are?!
廉頗は
ワナの場所が分かっているのか？
That can't be!
（李充）それはない！ 下からは
見えない場所にワナは仕掛けてある
The traps are set in positions you can't see from below!
It's not possible he could know!
知られるはずが…
Even if he can't see them, he can make a rough prediction of where they're located.
（蒙驁）見えていなくとも
おおまかな予想はできるぞ
Before he entered the stronghold,
砦に入る前
下から その全容が見える
he saw the whole layout from below.
Based on the shape of the mountain and the position of the fences, there aren't any suspicious places he can't detect.
柵の位置 山の形状から
怪しい所を発見できぬこともない
Th-Then he knew from the first time he saw the stronghold that there were traps?
（朱可）そ… それでは
最初に砦を見て ワナがあると？
（馬令）い… いや しかし
仮に… 仮に予測がついたとしても
B-But even if he... Even if he did predict where the traps were,
once he entered the stronghold, he would no longer be able to see the whole layout.
一度 砦に入れば
その全容は見えなくなります
It's impossible to follow the correct route in this complicated maze from memory!
いっときの記憶だけで
この複雑な迷路の―
正しい道順を進むことなど―
不可能です！
（蒙驁）それをやるのが―
If there's anyone who can do that, it's Lian Po.
廉頗じゃろうて
ンンッ… またワナをかわした
（郭叫）もう５合目までは来てるぞ
He avoided another trap!
He's already made it to the fifth level!
All right! Raise the flags!
（側近Ａ）よ～し 旗を掲げよ！
将軍の示す道に 間違いはないぞ！
The path the general is pointing us in can't be wrong!
Right!
( Flag - Lian )
（魏兵）オッ… 見ろ！
Look!
（蒙驁）ついに来たか
Finally... coming, are you?
廉頗 わしは十分 知っておるのじゃ
I'm well aware, Lian Po.
おぬしが
この迷路の攻略図を脳裏に描ききり
I knew full well that you could draw a map for attacking this maze in your mind
それを狂いなく
実践できる天才であることを
and that you could unerringly put it into practice.
よ～く知っておる　故に―
I know you're a genius.
And for that reason...
わしは
おぬしの さかしさを逆手に取る
that I will use your cleverness against you!
動かせ！
Move!
あっ！
（朱可）こ… これは
Wh-What is this?
They're creating new routes that lead to traps?!
ワナへとつながる新しい道が
出来上がった！
（馬令）行った！
They're going!
かかった！
（朱可）かかったぞ！
We've got them! We've got them!
My lord!
（側近たち）殿！
Lord!
Lian Po...
廉頗 おぬしを討つために―
the greatest strength of this stronghold I spent 40 years developing
四十数年 練っていた この砦の
最大の武器は―
おぬしが 事前に攻略した迷路を…
is a maze that you overcame in advance.
（魏兵たち）ウワッ…
（蒙驁）
あとから作り替えられることじゃ
After that, I just had to reshape it.
（魏兵）行き止まりだと！
A dead end?!
（廉頗）ほう…
Fire!
射て！
（信）後ろで…
I know...
本陣で何か起こってるのは分かるが
that something's going on at the headquarters behind me.
But I don't have time to divert attention to that right now.
今は そんな所まで気を回せねえ
今…
Right now...
If I take my eyes off this guy for an instant
こいつから目を離せば 即…
I'll be send to the next world!
あの世行きだ
Lord Xin...
（渕(えん)）信どの…
（渕）隣の伍(ご)と共に戦え！
１歩も引くんじゃないぞ！
Fight with your neighboring Wu!
Don't retreat a single step!
The opponents for the mounted units are mounted soldiers!
（楚水(そすい)）騎馬隊の相手は騎馬だ！
歩兵は下がれ！
皆の者 全てをこの一戦に懸けよ！
All foot soldiers, get back!
Everyone, we're risking everything on this fight!
（楚水）信どの
Lord Xin, leave the direction of the unit to me.
隊の指揮は お任せを
その代わり どうか―
In exchange, please...
あなたの手で 輪虎の首を！
Take down Lun Hu!
悪いな 渕さん 楚水
Sorry Mr. Yuan. Chu Shui.
He did an excellent job stopping my charge.
見事に進撃の足を止められた
輪動(りんどう)で兵が消耗したせいもあるが
It's partially because of my depletion of soldiers,
but it's primarily due to the Feixin Unit's strength.
何より 止めに入った飛信隊が強い
Both their mounted soldiers
騎馬も 歩兵も
and their foot soldiers.
そして それに呼応して
ほかの隊も戦に加わり奮戦している
And in response to that, the other units are fighting even harder.
In other words, the source of this part of the State of Qin Army's morale...
つまり
この辺り一帯の秦国軍の士気の源
それは 飛信隊の隊長 信！
is the Feixin Unit Captain, Xin.
この若者だ　彼が
実質的に将の役目を担っているんだ
This youngster.
He's substantially filling the role of general.
His fighting strength aside,
武の力は ともかく あの年で―
his ability to inspire people to this degree at this age
これほど人を引き付ける力は
自分には なかった
is beyond even my own.
This youngster truly is...
本当に この若者は…
Do you know just how heavy what
you're carrying right now is?
今 背負っているものの重大さが
分かっているかい？ 飛信隊の信
Xin of the Feixin Unit.
If you fall here, the entire State of Qin Army will collapse.
君が倒れれば
ここの秦国軍は総崩れとなり―
僕らは とっとと蒙驁を討ちに行く
And we'll go take down Meng Ao in no time.
Quit yammering!
ほざいてろ！
If you get slain by me, then we'll win the central battle!
てめえのほうこそ 俺に討たれて
中央の戦いは こっちの勝ちだ！
ジャマが―
Everything that was in the way... is gone!
消えた！
When you're fighting on horseback, a sword wound to the thigh is fatal.
馬上の剣戟(けんげき)で ももをやられるのは
致命的だよ
（信）クッ…
Dammit...
（信）しまった…
グアーッ！
A Single Moment
End